Array formulas. We've looked at how to analyze
数组公式 。 我们已经看了如何分析
the data for the quality of the exams, not necessarily looking at the
数据来得知考试的质量，
quality of students. We're looking at what questions in our exam
沒必要看学生的素质。 我们在考试里所看到的问题
contribute towards the end marks. And I think we can
有助於最後的成绩。 我 认为我们可以
say that we've come to a conclusion that question 2 doesn't really help.
说，我们已经得出一个结论， 问题2一點帮助都沒有。
It's not different from question 1, so of course we can just
这问题1没什麽不同，所以 当然我们可以
clear content, throw everything away. But
清除内容，扔掉所有一切。 但
that's not what I want. I manually inputted everything, so I want to keep
这不是我想要的。 我手动输入所有数据，所以我要保留
the values
值
but still I want to have the ability to analyze.
但我仍希望有能力分析。
So I could filter, but
这样我就可以筛选，但
the way the filtering works in Excel, is you can only filter in this direction
Excel中筛选的方式是你只能对这个方向筛选，
you can only filter on rows, and you can't filter on columns.
你只能筛选行，你不能筛选栏。
And that's exactly what I want, because I want to filter out one question and I
而这正是我想要的，因为我要筛选掉一个问题，
want to filter out
我要筛选掉
one student. So what I need to do
一位学生。 因此，我需要做的
is change my data, transpose my data into being in a different direction.
是改变我的数据，把资料以不同的方向移项。
So how to do that? What I can do is I made another worksheet,
那要怎麽做呢？ 我所能做的就是我另开工作表 ，
called exam transposed where I want to transpose my data.
名称为exam transposed，我想将 我的数据转置。
Excel has a function for that I can just say
Excel中有一个功能可以做到，
TRANSPOSE() type it in the formula bar. There we go,
就是在公式栏中键入TRANSPOSE（）。 开始罗，
TRANSPOSE() and I select the array of data
键入TRANSPOSE（），我选择数据数组
that I want you to transpose and then I hit control shift enter.
我要你转置的数据数组，然后我 按control shift enter。
So what I get now is just
所以，我现在只得到
one cell because as we've seen in a previous video I haven't given Excel
一个单元格，因为如我们在先前的视频所看到的，我没有给Excel
the room, the space
空間，
to plot the entire array. So if I want to have
绘制整个数组的空间。 所以，如果我想要
everything transposed, I need to make sure there's enough room in my worksheet
转置每个数据，我需要 确保我的工作表有足够空间来处理
to plot everything. So how much room do we need?
。 那么我们需要多少空间呢？
Well we have 16 rows so that will be 16 columns,
好了，我们有16行，所以会有16 列，
and we have 14 columns currently, so there will be 14
而我们目前有14列，所以需要14行
rows. So if we go back to our transpose worksheet we make sure that we make enough
因此，如果我们回到我们要转置 工作表，我们要确保我们有足够
room
空间给行列，然后我们可以用 TRANSPOSE（）函数与control shift enter，
making it into an array formula and now we get the result of the entire array.
使之成为一个数组公式，现在我们 得到数组阵列的结果。
So what was previously one row is now in a transposed version
那么，先前的一行现在变成转置後的一列了
Well first of all, we want to have the results in a different direction
那么首先，我们希望结果出现在不同的方向
but I also want to point out an important difference in Excel functions.
但我也想指出 Excel函数里重要的区别。
Some functions are array functions
某些函数属於数组函数
for instance, TRANSPOSE(). If you enter it you already see as an argument
例如，TRANSPOSE()。 如果你输入它，你已经看到作为一个参数
you need to put in an array so the transpose is
你需要把它放入数组中，所以转置
an array function in a sense. It always operates on an array,
某种意义上也有数组功能。 它总是在阵列上运行，
there's no other way. You can't put in a number, it doesn't know how to transpose
没有其他方式。 你不能放入一个数字，它不知道如何
a number.
将一个数字转置。
However other functions like the subtract function
但是其他 函数，
that we've seen in a previous video they not are
如我们已经在先前的视频看到的subtract函数，
inherently array formulas, but you can make them into array formulas
他们在本质不是数组公式 ，但你可以使他们成为数组公式，
by giving them a range as an argument and then
藉由给他们一个范围作为参数 进而
they can be made to work on all the pairs. So some functions
它们可对所有行列组运行。 所以，有些函数
are array and others can be made array
是数组而其它函数可变成数组
and that's also what the exercises of this video will be about.
而这也是这部影片所将要练习的。